翻译  落安  西西  ellaxinxin
翻译  Liv  小酸奶  肉松
翻译  寐兮  依俊听杰
西语顾问 IrinaPB  校对 喃喃
时间轴  姜姜  dreamdragon  喃喃
后期  8T   虫虫不咬人
总监  喃喃
#更多精彩请关注新浪微博@SubsKing @zimuzu#
孩子  你在吗
我在厨房
他伤得很重
He's really, it's really messed up.
孩子  我不知道怎么办
看着门  小心点
Watch the door, okay?
这两个小伙子  他们
你好  会说英语吗
Hey, hello. Habla English?
你是她儿子吗
Hey, are you the son?
我是她孙子
Grandson.
我在开车的时候  突然听到一声响
她开车的时候撞了他
She hit-hit him while driving.
我想我撞到他了
-我的腿  -撞到了
- My leg. - El smack-o.
奶奶  别担心  没事的
可是他们很生气
这贱人开车碾了我兄弟
Look. Look. Just a crazy old biznatch who ran over my brother.
痛得不得了  好痛啊
It hurts so bad. It hurts so bad.
很严重
It hurts so bad.
看到没  他受伤了
-看  -就是这条腿
- Look at that. - Yeah, it's this one.
-我的腿  -她撞断了他的腿
- My leg. - She-she broke his leg.
然后她还踩了油门  这是肇事逃逸
And then she stood on the gas. It's a hit-and-run.
她重罪了我  这是重罪
She, she felonied me. That's a felony.
事情经过我都拍下来了
Got the whole thing right here.
-天呐  -等等
- Dios mio. - Okay, hold on. Hold on.
让我跟她谈谈
L-let me talk to her.
-快谈  -很好
- So, start talking. - Yeah, good.
-奶奶  没关系的  -发生了什么
看到没  他的腿完全不能着地
Look. He can't, he can't put any pressure on it.
我得靠着你
I need to lean on you, so...
我不是故意的
腿肯定断了
I think it's-it's definitely broken.
我的腿坏掉了
Es muy mal for my leg-o.
靠着壁炉台
Here. Lean up, lean up on the mantel.
你的电视剧不是要开演了吗  上楼去看电视吧
腿真的很疼
No, man, it really hurts.
撑住  再坚持一下
Just hang in there. Hang in there.
-是"坏掉"吗  -没错  就是坏掉
- "Muy mal"? - Yeah, it's muy mal.
他们说我麻烦大了
老兄
Dude.
哥们儿  你有麻烦了
Dude. Yes, si, problema.
不会出事的
-现在问题变两个了  -老兄
- And now dos problemas. - Dude!
没事的  我会处理
没错  两个大麻烦
Si, d-dos big problemas.
把音量调大  这样你才能听见  要调得很大
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're saying, man.
-老兄  -知道了
- Dude. - Si.
-老兄  -明白了
这里问题大了
We got a real problem here, si.
出事了
Yeah, si problema.
天呐  天呐
Dios mio. Dios mio.
朋友  你要怎么处理这断腿
Hey, amigo, what are you gonna do about this leg situation?
我得去看医生
I really need to see a doctor.
医生可不便宜  要花不少钱
A doctor, doctors ain't cheap. It's gonna cost.
你们俩得有人出医药费
Either you or her, somebody's got to pay.
你想要钱
You want money.
-是  -没错
- Yes! - Yeah, damn straight.
肇事逃逸  这可不是说笑的
Hit-and-run? It's no joke.
警察会怎么说
We're, what are the cops gonna say?
警察
Cops?
警察要来吗
They coming?
-可能会来  -这取决于你
- Y-yeah, yeah, maybe. - That's up to you, man.
警察--
They, the cops--
随时都有可能看到这盘录像带
they can be looking at this tape anytime now.
都取决于你
It's all up to you.
我的腿很疼
Oh, that's really bad.
你叫她"贱人"
you c-called her "Biznatch"?
-我没有... -是又怎么样
- I didn't... - Yeah, but whatever, man.
快说个办法  我腿可疼了
Please, hurry it up. I'm hurting here.
给钱  不然我就叫警察
Show us the green, or la policea is gonna come,
他们会把奶奶带走的哦
and they're gonna be taking granny away!
她会进监狱  你想这样吗
She's gonna go to jail. Do you want that?
没错  好好想想吧
Yeah, that's right, play it smart.
很好  谈谈价钱吧
Okay, good. So, let's talk dollar amounts.
你所做的一切--
For what you did to my--
不  不
No! No!
贱人
Biznatch.
绝命律师
第一季 第二集
孩子
Mijo?
怎么了
没什么  挺好的
那些人还在吗
他们走了
我有麻烦了  是吗
没有  奶奶
No, abuelita.
一切都好  他们不会再来打扰您了
-地毯上是什么  -我把辣茄酱洒了
孩子啊
Ay, mijo.
奶奶
A-abuelita.
-我来帮你  -不  不用  我快擦完了
您要错过电视剧了
好吧
Oh. Bueno.
你确定不用帮忙吗
交给我来处理吧
你真是好孩子
别忘了要用苏打水擦
是  是  别担心
喂  马上过来
Hi. Get over here.
到我奶奶家
Uh, my abuelita's.
叫上不瞌睡  让纳乔开货车来
Bring No-doze and tell Nacho to bring his van.
开门  我是法院工作人员
Open up! Officer of the court!
以法律之名  命你开门
Open up in the name of the law!
下午好  这...
Good afternoon. This --
冷静  冷静  我把手举起来
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. I'm showing hands.
我...我很放松  没有任何威胁
I'm -- I'm relaxed -- okay? -- Um, non-threatening.
敢动一下  你就死定了
You move, and you're dead.
明白
Got it.
似乎有点误会
Seems to be a misunderstanding.
这里有没有人叫贝茜·凯特尔曼
Is there, by any chance, a Betsy Kettleman here?
我不确定我现在
See, I'm not sure if this is a situation
应不应该看着您的眼睛
where I should or should not look you in the eye.
坐
Sit.
你是谁
Who are you?
你和那两个红发人渣是一伙的吗
Are you with those redheaded scumbags?
我叫詹姆斯·麦吉尔  是个律师
My name's James Mcgill. I'm an attorney.
我接到了委托人的电话
Uh, I got a call from some clients, uh,
说发生了一点事故
said something about an accident.
我不知道事故详情
I did not get any details.
我在您家前院看到了两个滑板
When I saw some skateboards in your front yard,
我想他们大概...
I assumed they might --
孩子
Mijo...
这人是谁  他和那些人是一起的吗
不  他只是个推销员  奶奶  我来处理
您要去哪里
我去拿点苏打水
孩子  我还能看见你洒的辣茄酱  别让它干了
奶奶  我会用苏打水擦  我保证  相信我
请您回楼上去吧
好  可我不想让它干了
如果干了  就擦不掉了
说吧
Talk.
让我有根据地推测一下这儿发生的事
I'm gonna make an educated guess what happened here.
我的两名委托人
My two clients,
弗里克和弗拉克  两个"拖把头"
Frick and Frack, the mopheads,
遇到了一点交通事故  有点轻微的磕碰
were in a simple traffic accident, a minor fender bender,
但可能是他们站错了地方
but maybe they were on the wrong side of the street,
也可能是没有看马路两边
or they didn't look both ways.
谁都有可能
It could happen to anyone.
我的委托人展示出了极差的判断力
My clients, exhibiting extremely poor judgment,
居然一路跟着您奶奶
uh, followed your grandmother
到了这间温馨别致的房子
to this delightful, well-tended home.
而现在  我推测
Now, at this juncture, I'm deducing
他们说了或做了一些过分的事
that they said or did something that...crossed a line,
而您自有您的道理
And you, with some justification --
教训了他们一番
you put them in their place.
根据这辣茄酱污渍  他俩的下场可能有几种
Based on the salsa stain there, could have gone a couple ways.
底线是...不是说来恶心你
The bottom line -- not to be morbid,
但如果他们死了  我猜我...
but if they're dead, um, I'm guessing that I'm...
我应该...  应该...
I'm gonna -- I'm gonna -- yeah, I'm gonna go
积极乐观地离开  就当他们没来过
with glass half full here and say they're not.
我是说  如果他们还活着
Uh, my point is, if they're still alive,
何必杀我们呢  何必呢
why kill us? Why?
就因为一点误会  或者因为我们太蠢
Because of a misunderstanding? Our own stupidity?
何必把你奶奶漂亮的房子弄脏呢
Why mess up your lovely abuelita's place?
为什么不直接说最核心的部分
Why jump to the nuclear option?
我的意思是让事情简单一些
See, I'm saying keep it simple.
我会带上我愚蠢的委托人
I will collect my moronic clients, and --
然后立刻消失
poof! -- We are gone.
你和你可爱的奶奶
Neither you nor your lovely abuelita
永远都不会再见到我们  我保证
will ever lay eyes on us ever again, guaranteed,
签字盖章并交付[指一文件作成]
signed, sealed, and delivered.
假设  他们还活着的话
Assuming, you know, that they're still breathing.
你口才不错啊
You got a mouth on you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
起来
Get up.
那边
That way.
那边吗  好的  这就去
That way. Y-yeah, sure. Why not?
怎么  我来给他们松绑吗
So, what -- I should cut 'em loose?
都是他  都是他的主意
It was him! It was all his idea!
不不不
No, no, no!
你闭嘴
You shut up!
你说什么
Say what?
他想敲诈你
He -- he wanted to scam you.
他说我们能轻易骗到两千块
He said we could clear 2 grand, easy.
你敲诈我吗
You punking me?
你想敲诈我的奶奶吗
Are you punking my abuelita?
他撞到了头
He hit his head.
他根本不知道自己在说什么
He doesn't know what he's saying.
为了什么
For what?
为什么你会得到两千块
For what are you getting 2 grand?
只要跟踪你的奶奶
It was for going after your grandma,
在她的车前摔一跤然后要挟她
just for taking a header over her car and then b-bracing her.
都是他的主意  我发誓  是这个律师
It was him, I swear! It was the lawyer!
你是谁  为什么要跟着我
Who are you?! Why are you after me?!
我能解释的  你一定会笑的
I can explain. It's -- you're gonna laugh.
我是个律师  你可以看我的身份证  好吗
It's so -- I'm a lawyer. I -- check my I.D., okay?
但我在行骗
But I was running a scam.
-骗我的奶奶吗  -不不
- On my abuelita?! - No, no!
不是针对你奶奶  也不是你
Not on your abuelita, not on you.
有个叫贝茜·凯特尔曼的女人
There's a woman named Betsy Kettleman.
我提到了她
I mentioned her.
她嫁给了克雷格·凯特尔曼
She's married to Craig Kettleman.
他是伯纳利欧县的财务主管
He's the treasurer of Bernalillo County.
我想做他的生意  因为
I wanted his business 'cause...
他从县里挪用了一百五十万
he stole a million and a half bucks from the county.
从现在起他可能随时被指控挪用公款
He's gonna be indicted for embezzlement any day now.
对我来说这是个好案子  很大曝光率
This is a good case for me -- a lot of publicity.
我可以借此扬名
I'll get my name out, and...
不管怎样  我以为如果我让这两个人
Anyway, I thought if I had these two
滑着小滑板敲诈凯特尔曼太太
run their little skateboard hustle on Mrs. Kettleman,
而我可以拯救她
I could, you know, rescue her.
过来平息风波
Come in, throw some oil on troubled waters,
我就能得到他们的委托
and, yeah, I'd get their business.
这就是全部计划
That was the plan.
但事实是你可爱的奶奶
But it turns out your lovely abuelita --
她开的车
she drives a car...
非常像凯特尔曼家里的车
...that's a whole lot like the Kettle-mobile.
所以这两个天才敲诈错了人
So, these two geniuses ran their little stunt on the wrong one.
所以是我倒蚀把米
So, joke's on me.
就这么简单
I -- simple as that.
他去哪儿
Where's he going?
跟我说说  好吗
Talk to me, okay?
你以为我是谁  他在拿什么东西
Who do you think I am? What is he getting?
我行骗为了得到客户
I was running a scam to get a client.
我犯了个错误  就这些了
I made a mistake. That's all this is.
天哪
Oh, geez.
你不需要
Y-you don't need...
这不是...我会说的  好吗
That's not... I'll talk, okay?
告诉我你想知道什么
Tell me what you want to know!
你觉得  你觉得我是谁啊
Who do -- who do you think I am?
动口不动手好吗
Hey, use your words, okay?
干嘛
What?
你知道我闻到了什么吗
You know what I smell?
我闻到了谎言的气味
I smell lies.
我闻到了猪肉的味道
I smell pork.
不  不要这样
No, that's not necessary.
我们知道你是跟警察一伙  问题是哪个警方
Okay, we know you're with the heat. The question is, who?
-本地警方还是联调局  -都不是
- Local? FBI? - No, no, no.
-还是禁毒署  -我是个律师
- D.E.A.?! - No, I'm a lawyer.
去我的衣服口袋里翻  就在那里
Just reach in my pocket right now -- right there!
说实话
Truth.
那就是实话
That is the truth!
我是律师  我通过了司法考试  随便问
I'm a lawyer! Guys, I passed the bar! Ask me anything!
别问合同法就行  我每天都会到法庭去
Not contract law, okay? I'm down at the courts every day!
那些人都认识我
People know me!
我是那里的熟脸  真的
I'm a known quantity -- I am!
我是特工杰弗里·斯蒂尔  联调局的
I'm -- I'm special agent Jeffrey Steele, FBI.
-联调局  -联调局
- FBI? - FBI.
我是卧底  知道吗  被你发现了
I'm undercover, okay? You got me.
我是重要人物
I'm the tip of the spear,
释放我才是明智之举
and releasing me would be the smart move.
听见了吗
You hear that shit?
我跟你说了这桩买卖好得有点离奇
I told you the business was too good.
我就知道  我告诉过你
I knew it. I told you.
我来好吗
Can I?
好吧  特工先生  斯蒂尔
Okay, uh, special agent, uh, Steele?
杰弗里·A·斯蒂尔
Jeffrey A. Steele.
好吧  斯蒂尔特工  我们惹上什么案子了
Okay, agent Steele, what business are we in?
-什么案子  -你在调查我们  不是吗
- Business? - You're investigating us, right?
为了什么  我们做了什么
For what? What did we do?
-我们卖什么  -毒品
- What do we sell? - Drugs.
-什么毒品  -第二十一条法令
- What kind of drugs? - Uh...It's Title 21,
附件二到附件五  包括第二部分
Schedule II through Schedule V, including Part "B."
我们在局里就是这么叫的
That's what we call them down at the bureau.
特遣队的代号是
It's -- the task force
"打倒国王行动"
is designated "Operation King Breaker."
-"打倒国王"  -所以...
- "King Breaker"? - So...
这么说我是国王了
That makes me the king!
我来吧
Can I?
行了
All right.
从你嘴里吐出的下一个字必须是真话
The next words out of your mouth got to be the truth.
听明白了吗
You understand?
你是谁
Who are you?
我是詹姆斯·摩根·麦吉尔  我是律师
I'm James Morgan Mcgill. I'm a lawyer.
我是为了开拓业务  这是真的
I was trolling for business, okay? That's the truth.
你去找本圣经来  我会对它发誓的
Now, you find a bible, I'll swear on it.
"打倒国王行动"  联调局  是怎么回事
Okay, what about, uh, Operation, uh, King Breaker, FBI?
是我编的  对不起  对不起
I made it up, okay? I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
我不认识你  也不想认识
I don't know you. I don't want to.
这就是个错误  是我的错  行吗
Uh, this was a mistake, oka-- it's my mistake, okay?
我负全责
I take full and complete responsibility,
不过我真的不认识你们任何人
but I don't know any of your names,
而且我有严重的脸盲症
and I got a bad case of face-blindness.
你放了我们  我们会忘记今天发生的事
You let us go, we're gonna forget this happened.
伙计们  我们会忘记  是不是
Guys, we're gonna forget, right?
快点头
Nod your heads.
行了吗
Okay?
只要你们放我们走...
So, if you just let us go and just --
我们只想回家
We want to just go... home.
给他们松绑吧
I say cut 'em loose.
他说他是联调局的  他都承认了
He said he was FBI. He admitted it.
当时你用剪钳威胁他
You had your wire cutters on him.
他可能是随便编出来的
He would have said anything.
联调局的人会雇那两个火柴棍吗
You really see the FBI hiring those two flaquitos?
可能是吧
Maybe.
无缘无故杀死一名律师得不到任何好处
Croaking a lawyer for no reason is bad business.
如果他失踪了  会有人来找他的
He goes away, someone's gonna come look for him.
他们闯进了我的房子
They walked into my house.
他们对我奶奶不敬
They disrespected my abuelita.
他们叫她"婊子"
They call her "Biznatch"!
就这么放他们走吗
And they just walk?!
那个律师怎么办
What about the lawyer?
他很尊重你
He's giving respect.
好吧
Okay.
"詹姆斯·M·麦吉尔
"James M. Mcgill.
你可以信赖的律师"
A lawyer you can trust."
我知道去哪找你  詹姆斯·麦吉尔
I know how to find you, James Mcgill.
听明白我的话了吗
Understand what I'm saying?
明白
Yeah.
起来
Up.
好了吗
Okay?
带他回自己的车上
Take him back to his car.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这是明智之举
Uh, uh, this is -- this is good.
-这是正确的选择  谢谢你  -走吧
- This -- this is right. Thank you. - Come on.
那...那他们怎么办
What -- what -- what about them?
-走吧  -哦对
- Come on. - Yeah, right.
-走吧  -好吧
- Come on. - Uh, yeah, right.
你要去哪
Yo, where you going?
等等  我能说一句吗
Uh, wait. Can I -- can I say something?
-你去哪  -你能放了他们吗
- Where you going? - Can you let them go?
-放了他们吧  -你脑袋不好使吗
- Just let them go. - Are you stupid?
他们罪不至死  是我指使他们的
They don't deserve to die. I put them up to it.
我罪不至死  他们也是
I don't deserve to die, but they don't, either.
我要剥了他们的皮  就像野猪一样
I'm gonna skin them, like javelinas!
别管他们了  他们只是蛀虫
Forget about them! They're insects!
他们...想想他们的母亲
They're -- hey, think about their mother.
我唾弃他们的妈妈
I spit on their mama!
她是个温柔的小女人  她...还是个寡妇
She is a sweet little lady. She -- she's a widow.
她整天拼命工作  没日没夜
She works hard all day, every day,
就像他们外婆一样  从早干到晚
Just like her mother before her, from dawn till dusk,
天天为那些富人擦地板
Scrubbing the floors of rich people.
她连走路都要拄着拐杖
She needs a cane to walk, you know?
她得了关节炎  但还是天天干活
She's got arthritis. And still, she works every day.
为了她自己吗  当然不是
What -- for herself? No. No.
是为了他们  为了他们俩
For them -- for these two,
她的儿子们  她的宝贝
her boys, her apples of her eye.
你想说他们不配拥有这样的母亲吗
You say they don't deserve her?
可能吧  但他们是她唯一的支柱
Maybe so, but they're all she's got.
现在你要是把他们开膛破肚
Now...You turn them inside out,
我希望你想想会对她造成多大的打击
I want you to think about what happens to her.
不  那是他们的错
No, that's on them.
他们早该料到这个下场
They should have thought about that.
当我在你奶奶家时
When I was at your abuelita's place,
你本来准备放了他们
you were gonna let them go.
我觉得那是因为你尽管强硬  但不失公道
Way I see it, that's because you're tough, but you're fair.
你是为了正义
You're all about justice.
我就是这个意思  正义
That's what I'm saying -- justice.
这两个猪脑子  大嘴巴
These -- these two shit-for-brains? These big-mouths?
你已经把他们打得半死
You -- you already beat the living hell out of them.
你觉得他们会忘记今天的教训吗
Do you think they're ever gonna forget today?
不可能的  过了十年
Never -- 10 years from now,
他们回想起来仍然会尿裤子
They're still gonna be crapping their jockeys.
-那还不够  -好吧
- It's not enough. - Okay, okay.
那么罪罚应该相当
Then let's talk proportionality.
他们有罪  成立
They're guilty -- oh, agreed.
现在由你来决定该如何正确量刑
Now you have to decide, what's the right sentence?
像法官一样
Like a judge.
你听过汉谟拉比法典吗
Ever hear of the Code of Hammurabi --
量刑判罪  以眼还眼
Let the punishment fit the crime, eye for an eye?
以眼还眼
Eye for an eye.
你是说让我戳瞎他们
You want me to blind them.
不  不是
No, no.
他们只是胡说八道
All they did was trash-talk.
那我就把他们的舌头割了
So I cut their tongues out!
等下  我建议...
Wait. See, I'm advising...
你要量刑判罪
that you make the punishment fit the crime.
量刑判罪
Punishment fit the crime.
哥伦比亚领带刑  我要割开他们的喉咙
Columbian neckties -- I cut their throats,
再把他们说谎的舌头从刀缝中拉出来
and then I pull their lying tongues through the slits!
"婊子"
"Biznatch"!
或者  你可以揍到他们眼圈发黑
Or you -- you could give them black eyes.
眼圈发黑  那算什么
Black eyes? That ain't nothing.
你看那边那位  伙计
That one there, homes --
他早就被揍得鼻青脸肿了  蠢货
He already got a black eye, fool.
少帮腔
Stop helping.
或者可以把他们的脚扭断
Or you could sprain their ankles.
-扭断  -他们不是喜欢滑滑板吗
- Sprain? - They're -- they're skateboarders, right?
他们就是这样敲诈别人的
That -- that's how they run their scam.
要是他们不能滑滑板
They can't skate.
你就相当于断了他们的财路
You -- you hit them where they live.
我才不会用扭的  贱人
I ain't spraining nothing, bitch.
我要打断他们的手臂  打断他们的腿
I'm gonna break their arms, and I'm gonna break their legs.
手臂  我们什么时候又扯到手臂上了
Arms? When -- when -- when did we get on to arms?
-我们...  -我要把他们的腿砍下来
- Let's... - I'm cutting their legs off.
你要这样也可以
But -- we could go that way,
我们之前说的是弄断
but...we were talking about breaking.
我觉得咱们方向有点偏了
I think we're heading in the wrong direction.
好的
Okay.
打断他们的腿
Break their legs.
几条腿
How many legs?
两条  他们有两条腿
Two -- they got two legs.
每人  一条腿
One leg -- each.
每人一条吗
One leg -- each?
他们
They're --
每人一条  一共两条
One leg each, that's a total of two legs.
听我说
Uh, hey, look.
他们六个月不能玩滑板
They can't skateboard for six months,
而且会畏惧你一辈子
and they're scared of you forever.
让大家知道你才是老大
You show everybody that you are the man,
但你公平公正
but that you're fair, that you're just.
每人一条腿
One leg each.
很残忍  但也公平
That's tough, but it's fair.
好  按住他们  我没一整天闲工夫
All right, lay 'em out! I ain't got all day!
这里真他妈热
It's hotter than shit out here!
别动  这样只会更难受
Quit moving -- you're only gonna make it worse!
我们知错了  知错了
We're sorry! We're sorry!
看
Look it!
好样的  好样的
Hell, yeah! Hell, yeah!
他说他断了条腿  这下如他所愿
He said he had a broke leg -- now he's got one for real!
向你妈妈道歉  贱人
You -- tell your mama you're sorry, bitch!
另一个
Other one.
看  腿都转了一圈
Look -- it's backwards.
瞧好了
Check it out.
这条要快准狠
I'm gonna do this one real clean.
不  天呐  不
No! Oh, my god! No!
走回家啊  贱人
Walk home now, bitch!
闭嘴  别吵
Shut up! Shut up!
来了  来了  慢点  慢点
Here you go. Here you go. Easy, easy.
-你  疼  疼  -还有力气喊疼
- You -- you -- you -- aah! Aah! - Save your breath.
你是最烂的律师
You -- you are -- you are the worst lawyer,
史上最烂律师
The worst lawyer ever!
我为你谈判  免了你的死刑
Hey, I just talked you down from a death sentence...
-天呐  好疼  -只用服六个月的缓刑
- Oh, my god! Oh, my!- To six months' probation.
我是最棒的律师
I'm the best lawyer ever.
伙计  慢点
Dude, dude, dude, oh!
天呐  不
Oh, my god! Oh! No!
麻烦你
Could you, uh --
不好意思  我马上回来
Could you, um -- I'll be right back.
东西放信箱了吗
Ground yourself?
吉米  你放了吗
Jimmy, did you ground yourself?
看来你没有放
I don't think you grounded yourself.
老天
Jesus.
吉米  你不会醉成这样还开车吧
Jimmy, you didn't drive like this, did you?
天啊
Oh, no.
-没有  -我就知道
- No. - I knew it.
急诊单
查克
Chuck.
喝咖啡吗
Coffee?
行  谢了
Yeah, thanks.
只能喝清咖
You're gonna have to take it black.
牛奶喝完了吗
We're out of milk?
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
你怎么披着太空毯
Why are you in that space blanket?
你昨晚把手机带屋里了
You brought your cellphone in here last night.
在你裤子口袋里
It was in your pants pocket.
抱歉
Sorry about that.
我手机呢
Where, uh -- where is it?
在外面  我丢门外去了
Outside -- I threw it out the door.
好吧
Yeah.
我怎么回来的
How did I get here?
你车不在外面  应该是打车回的
Your car's not outside, so I'm assuming taxi.
没错
Right.
酒保不让我开车
Uh, the bartender... wouldn't let me drive.
你怎么披着太空毯
Why are you in that space blanket?
我说了  你把手机带进屋里了
I told you -- you brought your cellphone into my house.
查克  你...
Uh, Chuck, um, did you...
查克  你看了这个吗
Chuck, did you read this?
看了什么
Read what?
这份账单  你看到了吗
Uh, this, um, this bill -- did you read it?
急诊单  我瞟了一眼
Emergency-room bill -- yeah, I may have glanced at it.
从你裤子口袋里掉出来的
It fell out of your pocket.
查克  我知道你怎么想
Hey, Chuck, listen, I-I know how this looks.
我身无分文了  但突然
I'm down to my last dime, and, suddenly,
能出钱治疗断腿了  但这...
I'm paying for broken legs, but...
不是你想的那样
It's -- it's not that.
我发誓
I swear.
其实这是件好事
This represents a good thing, ultimately.
好吧
Okay.
我不会堕落回原来那个"风流吉米"
I-I'm not backsliding. This isn't Slippin' Jimmy.
好吧
Fine.
查克  你别披着太空毯了好吗
Take off the space blanket, will you, please, Chuck?
有用啊
It helps.
你别披着了行不行  我又没做错什么
Take off the space blanket. I didn't do anything wrong.
没你什么事  是你的手机
It has nothing to do with that. It was your phone.
把太空毯拿下来
Take off the space blanket.
为什么
Why?
查克  别披着了
Take off the space blanket, Chuck.
快点拿下来吧
Come on. Take off the blanket.
谢谢
Thank you.
我手机在前院吗
Front yard?
你记不记得昨晚扔哪了
Uh, do you have any idea where it landed?
不记得
No.
没有
没有  没有
No. No.
没有
No.
你还想要什么
What do you want?
什么都可以  别饿死我就行
Not to starve to death.
给你这个  可以吗
What do you say?
有活给我干吗
Got something for me?
朋友们  见证奇迹的时刻到了
It's showtime, folks.
语出1979年音乐电影《爵士春秋》
120法庭
格罗比斯  你的律师来了
Globis, lawyer.
我要杀了他
I'm gonna kill him.
"法官大人  对不起  我再也不敢了"
"Your honor, I'm very sorry. I'll never do it again."
说什么  这
Say what?! Just...
法官大人  对不起  我再也不敢了
Your honor, I'm very sorry, and I'll never do it again.
好了  皮尔森先生  站起来
Okay, Mr. Pearson, up you go.
站起来  好的
Up you go. All right.
这是什么
What's this?
我不是让你穿西装吗  不记得了吗
I told you a suit, remember?
你得看起来精神点
Told you you want to look sharp.
这可是我借给你的  记得还给我  走吧
That's a loaner, okay? I need it back. Let's go.
-偷盗且有前科  -那孩子就偷了块披萨而已
- Petty with a prior. - The kid took a slice of pizza.
-偷盗且有前科  -他父母简直一团糟
- Petty with a prior. - Look, the parents are a train wreck.
家里也没吃的  他很饿啊
There's no food in the house! He was hungry!
-偷盗且有前科  -求你了
- Petty with a prior. - Come on!
-你这贴纸还不够  -算了吧
- You're light on stickers. - Come on.
-五块  -你来真的
- $5. - You serious?
你就四张贴纸  得有五张才行
You got four. You need five.
这四张可是九十分钟的贴纸
There's four 90-minute stickers there.
你的车都停在这里六个小时零五分了
You've been here 6 hours and 5 minutes.
走到那边要十分钟
It takes 10 minutes to walk down here!
五块  要不你再去弄张贴纸
$5, or you go get another sticker.
你以为你谁啊
This makes you feel real important, huh?!
贴纸不够  不够个鬼
Not enough stickers! More stickers!
朋友们  见证奇迹的时刻到了
It's showtime, folks.
见证奇迹的时刻
It's showtime.
偷盗且有前科
Petty with a prior.
前科会跟随他一辈子的
Prior will stay on his sheet for life.
偷盗且有前科
Petty with a prior.
你这指控过于严重了
You're overcharging him.
偷盗且有前科
Petty with a prior.
那边那女的  她每次都少给我算
That lady up there -- she shorts me every time, okay?
这不是我的问题  这是你的问题
This is not a me problem -- this is a you problem.
这是见证奇迹的时刻
It's showtime.
怎么了  这可是电影台词
What? It's from a movie.
出口
-偷盗且有前科  -入店行窃  轻罪而已
- Petty with a prior. - Misdemeanor shoplifting.
-偷盗且有前科  -求你了  让我这一次
- Petty with a prior. - Come on. Meet me halfway.
-偷盗且有前科  -我很难办
- Petty with a prior. - I can't do it.
-偷盗且有前科  -那要不这样
- Petty with a prior. - Okay, or how about this?
我让那孩子认罪
I plead the kid to the sheet,
你延期宣判
but you give me a continued sentence.
六个月以后  如果他还是乖乖的
And in six months, if he's still clean,
那你就撤诉
You file for a dismissal.
求你了  你也不想这样和我耗时间吧
Come on. Is this how you want to spend your time?
那要不这些都给你吃
You can have the rest of these.
伯杰  你的律师来了
Berger, lawyer.
伯杰先生  我们之前见过对吧
Oh, Mr. Berger, we've met before, haven't we?
爱迪生先生  你和大发明家同名啊
Mr. Edison, like the inventor?
我是詹姆斯·麦吉尔
I'm James Mcgill.
我是你的律师
I'll be your lawyer.
没关系  法官决定去看你母亲了
Doesn't matter. Judge has got to see your mother.
你知不知道谁和你母亲长得像
Well, do you know anybody who looks like her?
不  你叔叔可不行
No, an uncle won't do it.
好的  着火了
Okay, so, a fire was started.
我们大家都明白
We all know that.
就像她现在这样  冷得直打颤
Freezing, shivering, as she is now.
事实上  就这件事写了一本书
In fact, wrote a book about it.
...做点饼干
...To make some cookies.
但是由于你...给了她这个名字...
But because you... ...Given her this name...
你可以看到这个人...
You can see that this man...
做出了...愚蠢的选择
Chose...A bonehead move.
你就是桥下的怪物
Like a troll under a bridge!
"要从此路过  亮出贴纸来"
"You must have the stickers, or you won't pass!"
此处有怪物  小心被吞食
Troll alert here -- don't feed it!
你们好  女士们
Chao chi c'ung, ladies.
晚上好  阮太太
Good evening, Mrs. Nguyen.
没有你的邮件
No mail.
维姬  马吉
Hey, Vicki, Maggie.
您没有留言
You have...Zero messages.
有顾客
Customer.
-什么  -有顾客找你  正在外面等候
- What? - For you -- a customer, waiting now.
我知道了  等我一分钟
Oh, uh, sure, sure. Uh, give me a minute.
请进  请进  我的办公室正在刷漆
Welcome, welcome. My office is being painted.
抱歉在这个临时接待...处
Excuse the temporary, uh...Quarters.
蛮温馨的
Wow. Cozy.
就我一个人
Just me.
屠库吓着你了吧
Tuco freaked you out, huh?
别担心  他不知道我来这里
It's cool. He doesn't know I'm here.
那么...您有何贵干
So, uh... What can I do for you?
我一直在想
I've been thinking about what you said
你在沙漠说过的话
out there in the desert.
那对你试图诈骗的夫妇
Those people that you were trying to scam --
他们偷了多少钱
How much did they steal?
我觉得  一百五十多万美元吧
Um, north of a million and a half bucks...I think.
那就是说  他们在某处藏了一百五十万
So, they have a million and a half bucks somewhere.
是现金么
In what, cash?
我不知道
I don't -- well...
你为什么问这个
Why are you asking me?
我打算抢他们
I'm gonna rip them off.
我喜欢打劫小偷
I like ripping off thieves
因为他们没法报警  他们孤立无援
'cause they can't go to the cops -- they have no recourse.
你告诉我他们的钱藏在哪儿
You point me at where they have their cash --
我会付你  怎么说来着
I'll pay you -- a what do you call it? --
中介费  付你百分之十  就是十万
A finder's fee -- call it 10%, 100 large.
你怎么会来找我呢
Well, uh, why w-- why would you come to me for that?
你不是早试过抢他们了么
You already tried ripping them off.
我只是继续你未完成的事业
I'm gonna finish what you started.
我没想抢他们
I-I wasn't trying to rip them off.
我只是想接他们的活儿
I-I just wanted their business.
好吧
Okay.
我不知道他们把钱放在哪里
I don't know where their money is.
你这么聪明  肯定能找到的
Smart guy like you could figure it out.
给我需要的信息  我们就皆大欢喜
If I know what I need to know, nobody gets hurt.
我们抢了他们  轻轻松松拿钱
We rip them off -- easy money.
听着  我是个律师  不是罪犯
Hey, look, I'm a lawyer, not a criminal.
你在逗我吗
You are shitting me.
我打破了底线  犯了错误
I crossed a line. I made a mistake.
我不会再犯  再也不会
I'm not doing that again, not ever.
你和屠库之间全靠我挡着
I got between you and Tuco.
要是我当时不帮你说话  你还能在这儿
Do you think you'd be here now -- I kept my mouth shut?
我很感激  算我欠你的
And I appreciate that. I owe you.
以后你要是有麻烦  当然没有更好
A-and if you're ever in trouble, god forbid,
法律上的麻烦
legal trouble,
我一定随叫随到  为你辩护
I will be there, 24-7, as a lawyer.
你有什么打算
What's your angle?
不  我没有打算
No -- no angle.
今天的事我不会对任何人讲
And I'm not saying anything about this to anybody.
因为我把你当成我的客户
As far as I'm concerned, you're a client.
而这只是一次咨询
This is a consultation,
你刚刚和我说的一切都会保密
and everything you just told me is privileged.
要敢说出去  你就死定了
You rat, you die.
放心  保证不说
And that, too, yes.
什么时候想通了打给我
For when you figure out you're in the game.
我不会参与的
I'm not in the game.
我保证
I-I promise.